Autograph File, B: Guide.
Autograph File, B,
- Banville, Théodore de, 1823-1891. Toast à Madame J. Rousset. A.MS.s.; [n.p.] 14 Aug 1871., 1s.(3p.)
  Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, Dec. 1963.
- Banville, Théodore de, 1823-1891. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.]., 1s.(1p.)
  Removed from a copy of Odes funambulesques.
  *65M-76. Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, 22 Nov 1965.
- Baour Lormian, Pierre Marie François Louis, 1770-1854. A.L.s. to [Mme. ] Coquillard; Toulouse, 18 Sep [1814], 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (20). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Barante, Amable Guillaume Prosper Brugière, baron de, 1782-1866. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 18 Oct 1857., 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (20a). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Barb, Pierre. T.L.s. to André Brule; Paris, 8 Jul 1925., 1s.(2p.)
- Barb, Pierre. T.L.s. to James Hazen Hyde; Paris, 10 Jul 1925., 1s.(1p.)
- Barbauld, Anna Letitia (Aikin) 1743-1825. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 13 Jan [ ], 1s.(1p.)
  Fragment only.
- Barbauld, Anne Letitia (Aiken), 1743-1825. A.L.s. to [ ] Bergnor [?]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  *45M-181(28) Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Barbé-Marbois, Francois, marquis de, 1745-1837. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 14 Messidor [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  *54M-112. Purchased from Gardner C. Turner, 7 July 1954.
- Barbé-Marbois, Francois, marquis de, 1745-1837. A.L.s. to [ ] Deters; Philadelphia, 14 Jun 1786., 1s.(2p.)
- Barber, John Vincent, fl. 1830. A.L.s. to [ ]; Birmingham, 3 Apr 1828., 1s.(1p.)
- Barber, John Vincent, fl. 1830. A.L.s. to A[ ] Cooper; Birmingham, 8 Jan 1820., 1s.(1p.)
- Barber, John Vincent, fl. 1830. A.L.s. to John Smith; London, 30 Jun 1828., 1s.(1p.)
  Also a postscript from T. Phillips.
  Bequest of E. J. Wendell, 1918.
- Barber, Joseph B A.L.s. to R P Ranny; Rome, 19 Jul 1838., 1s.(1p.)
- Barber, Miles A.L.s. to John Stoughton, London, 25 Feb 1783., 1s.(3p.)
- Barber, Thomas A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(4p.)
- Barbèri, Andrea. Ritratto di Napoli. A.MS.s.; Rome, 21 Feb 1882., 1s.(1p.)
  *57M-94. Deposited by George Benson Weston, 27 Dec 1957. Later bequest.
- Barbey d'Aurevilly, Jules, 1808-1889. A.L.s. to [Charles] Giraud; [n.p., n.d.], 1s. (1p.)
  Removed from copy of his "Les miserables de m. Victor Hugo," (1862)
  Gratis, 1963.
- Barbier, Auguste, 1805-1882. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 1 Apr 1881., 1s.(3p.)
  *49M-187 (21) From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Barbour, James, 1775-1842. A.L.s. to Daniel Bryan; Washington, 20 Feb 1826., 1s.(2p.)
- Barclay, David A.L.s. to [ ] Holliday; [London] 15 Nov 1787., 1s.(1p.)
- Barfoot, J R, fl. 1830-1837. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barham, Richard Harris, 1788-1845. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 12 Jan [n.d.], 1s.(3p.)
- Barham, Richard Harris Dalton, 1815-1886. A.L.s. to [ ]; Bath, 12 Aug [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barham, Richard Harris, 1788-1845. A.L.s. to [ ]; Margate, 22 Aug [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barham, Richard Harris, 1788-1845. A.L.s. to [Mary Ann (Watts) Hughes]; [London ] 6 Mar 1843., 1s.(2p.)
  Annotated at end by Mrs. Hughes.
  *51M-145. Purchased with the Greenough fund from Elkin Mathews Ltd., 14 Jan 1952.
- [Barham, Richard Harris Dalton, 1815-1886 ] Drawing: [Portrait of Richard Harris Barham]; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  Annotated by Mary Ann (Watts) Hughes.
  *51M-146. Purchased with the Greenough fund from Elkin Mathews Ltd., 14 Jan 1952.
- Barham, Richard Harris, 1788-1845. D.S.; [n.p.] 26 Mar 1833., 1s.(1p.)
  Signature on receipt for money paid to J. Wilson.
- Barillon, J. J., seigneur de Morangis, d. 1741. A.L.s. to Lamoignon de Basville; Madrid, 10 Aug 1703., 1s. (4p.)
- Baring, Maurice, 1874-1945. A.L.s. to [ ]; France, 24 Aut 1918., 1s.(2p.)
- Barker, George A.L.s. to [ ]; Stamford, 25 Nov 1845., 1s.(3p.)
- Barker, George A.L.s. to [ ]; London, 7 Nov 1848., 1s.(2p.)
- Barker, George, A.L.s. to [ ]; London, 8 Nov 1848., 1s.(2p.)
- Barker, Joshua A. receipt; Hingham, 16 Jan 1772., 1s.(1p.)
- Barker, Robert, 1739-1806. MS.D.s.; [n.p.] 3 Jul 1787., 1s.(1p.)
  Description of patent for producing panorama pictures.
- Barker, Thomas, 1769-1847. A.L.s. to Edward Mangin; Bath, 17 Apr 1841., 1s.(4p.)
- Barker, Thomas Jones, 1815-1882. A.L.s. to Charles Lockey; [London?] 26 Jun 1849., 1s.(2p.)
- Barlow, Francis Channing, 1834-1896. A.L.s. to Charles [ ]; [n.p.] 5 Mar [ ], 1s.(4p.)
- Barlow, Francis Channing, 1834-1896. A. signature; Albany, 1 Apr 1867., 1s.(1p.)
- Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812. A.L.s.(photostat) to Elias Boudinot; Hartford, 10 Jan 1783., 5s.(5p.)
  Original in U.S. Archives.
  Received 1956.
- Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812. A.L.s. to Elisha Babcock; Hartford, 3 May 1784., 1s.(1p.)
- Barlow, Joel, 1754-1812. A.L.s.(photostat) to James Duane; Hartford, 14 Mar 1788., 2s.(2p.)
  Original in New York Historical Society.
- Barlow, Samuel Latham Mitchill, 1826-1889. A.L.s. to John B. Morean; [n.p.] 7 Feb 1865., 1s.(1p.)
- Barlow, Samuel Latham Mitchill, 1826-1889. A.L.s.to [Thomas H.] Morrell; [New York, n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barnard, Frederick Augustus Porter, 1809-1889. Letters to Samuel Bulkley Ruggles:
  - A.L.s.; New York, 9 Jun 1806., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; New York, 4 Apr 1876., 1s.(4p.) env.
  - A.L.s.; same, 25 Apr 1876., 2s.(5p.) env.
- Barnes, Albert, 1798-1870. A.L.s. to Joseph B. Boyd; Philadelphia, 29 Nov 1850., 1s.(1p.)
- Barnes, Albert, 1798-1870. A.L.s. to B. B. Edward; Philadelphia, 22 Jan 1837., 1s.(2p.)
- Barnes, Demas, 1827-1888. A. signature; Washington, 23 Mar 1867., 1s.(1p.)
- Barnes, William, 1801-1886. A.L.s. to Eric G. Robertson; Dorchester, 8 Aug 1885., 1s.(2p.) env.
  Purchased with the Kittredge fund, 25 Jan 1938.
- Barnes, William, 1801-1886. Letter to Charles Warne,1880 January 4., 1 folder.
  Concerning J. F. (John Fitzgerald) Pennie; removed from James Stevens-Cox's copy of Pennie's The royal minstrel, or, The witcheries of Endor: an epic poem, in eleven books (1817).
  *2008M-86. Removed from *EC85.B2638.Y817p.
- Barnett, George C A.L.s. to Henry Edwards; New York, 23 Feb 1884., 1s.(3p.) env.
- Barnett, John, 1802-1890. A.L.s. to [ ]; Monson Villa, 20 Jun 1852., 1s.(2p.)
- Barnett, Samuel Augustus, 1844-1913. A.L.s. to [Dr. ] Paton; [London] 18 Dec 1907., 1s.(2p.)
- Barnett, Samuel Augustus, 1844-1913. A.L.s. to [ ] Tawreg; [London] 5 Feb 1910., 1s.(2p.)
- Barnett, William, 1733-1789. A.L.s. to William Pollard; Newport, 29 Jun 1775., 1s.(4p.)
- Barnum, Nancy (Fish) Letters to E.W. Walker Co.
  - A.L.s. (P.H.Prindle); Bridgeport, 3 May 1893, 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s. (P.H.Prindle); same, 29 May 1893., 1s.(1p.)
- Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891. MS.L.s. to Lloyd [Stephens] Brice [i.e. Bryce]; London, 4 Nov 1889., 1s. (2p.)
  *43M-213. Purchased with the Sheldon fund from Mrs. Russell Law, 27 Oct 1943.
- Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891. MS.L.(contemporary copy?) to the editor of the [New York] Tribune; [New York, n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891. A.L.s. to S. C. Nickerson; Bridgeport, Conn., 1 Sep 1874., 1s.(1p.)
  With this is a cut signature of Barnum, dated April 1888.
- Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891. A.L.s. to [James] Redpath; Bridgeport, Conn., 30 Dec 1879., 1s.(1p.)
- Barnum, Phineas Taylor, 1810-1891. A. signature; New York, 15 Feb 1867., 1s.(1p.)
- Barnwell, Charles Frederick A.L.s. to [ ] Pettigrew; Wobun Place, 4 Jul [ ]., 1s.(2p.)
- Barr, Amelia Edith Huddleston, 1831-1919 A.L.s. to [ ] Stoddart; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barrès, Maurice, 1862-1923. A.L.s. to Jules Bois; Paris, 31 Jan 1894., 1s.(1p.) env.
  *64D-242. Purchased with the Friedman fund, Sept 1964.
- Barrès, Maurice, 1862-1923. A.L.s. to [ ]; Nancy, 21 Jun [188-?], 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (22). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Barrès, Maurice, 1862-1923. A.L.s. to [Paul Fort]; [n.p.] 29 Apr 1914., 1s.(1p.)
  *49M-187 (23). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Barrett, George, 1767-1842. A.L.s. to Alaric Alexander Watts; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Barrett, George, 1767-1842. Receipt A.MS.s. to George Morant; [n.p.] 21 Mar 1827., 1s.(1p.)
  Bequest of E.J. Wendell 1918.
- Barrett, James, 1814-1900. A.L.s. to C.F. Houghton; Woodstock, Vt. 15 Jun 1863., 1s.(2p.)
- Barrett, John, 1866-1938. A.L.s. to Benjamin W. Austin; Bangkok, Siam, 11 Sep 1895., 1s.(2p.)
- Barrett, John, 1866-1938. Letters to Erastus Brainerd:
  - T.L.s.; Washinton, 24 Feb 1908., 1s.(1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 7 May 1908., 1s.(1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 11 Oct 1908., 1s.(1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 18 Oct 1908., 1s.(1p.)
- Barrett, John, 1866-1938. 3 letters to Erastus Brainerd
  - T.L.s.; Washington, 29 Mar 1909., 1s.(2p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 2 Jun 1913., 1s.(1p.)
  - T.L.s.; same, 2 Jun 1913., 1s.(1p.)
- Barrett, L H A.L.s. to Stephen Hoyt; New Orleans, 3 Sep 1864., 1s.(2p.)
- Barrett, William Sale of land to his brother, Daniel April 16, 1733
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. [What every woman knows]. End of 3rd act. A.MS.(unsigned); [n.p., 1918], 3s.(3p.)
  Revised ending for play.
  *55M-164. Presented by Mrs. H. M. Booth, 24 Jan 1956.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to John Lane; London, 18 May 1904., 1s. (3p.)
  *69M-104. Deposit from Hilles Library, Feb 1970.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to [ ] Gray; [London] 12 May 1931., 1s.(1p.)
  *44BM-4. Gift of Albert F. Bigelow, June 1945.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to [ ] Gray; [London] 7 May 1930., 1s.(1p.)
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to Charles Frohman; [London] 29 Oct 1901., 1s.(3p.)
  About changes in Act 3 of Quality street; enclosing 2 f. of typescript with autograph revisions embodying the changes (4p.)
  *55M-50. Gift of Miss Phyllis Robbins, 19 Oct 1955.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to James Dowell [?]; [London] 26 Apr 1913., 1s.(2p.)
  *44BM-3. Gift of Albert F. Bigelow, June 1945.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to Oliver Brett, 3d viscount Esher; [London] 25 Mar 1931., 1s.(1p.)
  *47M-354. Gratis, 1948.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to [ ]; London, 15 May 1888., 1s.(2p.)
  Removed from *50-772.
- Barrie, Sir James Matthew, bart., 1860-1937. A.L.s. to [Dame Ellen] Terry; [London] 8 Oct 1904., 1s.(3p.)
  About casting Alice sit-by-the-fire; with printed program of first performance 5 Apr 1905.
  *49M-101. Purchased with the F. E. Chase fund from Ifan Kyrle Fletcher, 19 Jan 1950.
- Barrington, Daines, 1727-1800. A.L.s. to [Hugh Percy, 1st duke of Northumberland?]; [London?] 4 May 1773., 1s.(3p.)
  *47M-373 (7). Estate of Samuel Henshaw. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. Alfred M. Tozzer,; Mrs. Thomas Barbour, and Miss Gertrude A. Thurston, June 1943.
- Barrington, Daines, 1727-1800. A.L.s. to Thomas Percy, bp. of Dromore; [London] 14 Jun 1776., 1s.(3p.)
  Gift of C. N. Greenough, 5 Dec 1927.
- Barrington, Shute, bp. of Durham, 1734-1826. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 19 Oct 1768., 1s.(2p.)
  *45M-443. Gift of Harry L. Bailey, 20 Dec 1945.
- Barrington, William Wildman Barrington, 2d viscount, 1717-1793. A.L.s. to William Henry Cavendish Bentinck, 3d duke of Portland; Beckett, 13 Aug 1778., 1s. (3p.)
  Gift of E.J. Wendell, 1918.
- Barron, Elwyn Alfred, 1855- A.L.s. to Erastus Brainerd; Chicago, 21 Dec 1885., 1s.(1p.)
- Barron, Samuel, 1809-1888. A.L.s. to John Earle; Norfolk, 14 Sep 1839., 1s.(3p.)
  Includes A.D.s. (John L. Leary); Boston, 26 Sep 1839.
  *45M-181 (29). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Barrow, John S A.L.s. to Francis Parkman; New York, 29 Dec 1879., 1s.(3p.)
  Removed from Soc 5055.1.5*.
- Barrow, Pope A.L.s. to Evan Parke Howell; Washington 21 Dec 1882., 1s.(2p.)
- Barrows, Samuel June, 1845-1909. T.L.s. to Arthur Wentworth [Hamilton] Eaton; Washington, 22 Feb 1899., 1s.(1p.)
  Removed from MS Am 873.2.
- Barry, Adrienne. TS. of letter to the Editor of The new republic; New York, 23 Jun 1930., 1s.(1p.)
  Discusses Herbert David Croly.
  *52M-157. Presented by Mr. David Sidney Jensen, 18 Sept 1952.
- Barry, Sir Charles, 1795-1860. A.L.s. to Madam [ ]; Westminister; 2 Apr 1849., 1s.(2p.)
- Barry, Henry, 1750-1822. A.L.s. to Robert Barry; Bath, 9 Oct 1822., 1s.(3p.)
  With A.MS. annotations on a separate sheet; [n.p., n.d.]. 1s.(1p.)
  Recat. fr. *74-842.
- Barry, John, 1745-1803. Printed D.s.; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
  Blank certificate for share in a privateer's prizes.
  Gift of Charles H. Taylor, 11 Sept 1929.
- Barry, John Daniel, 1866- Letters to Edmund Clarence Stedman:
  - A.L.s.; New York, 23 Mar 1897., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Boston, 30 Jun 1898., 1s.(3p.)
- Barry, John O'Brien Milner, 1815-1881. A.L.s. to Mrs. [ ] White; [n.p.] 24 Sep 1866., 1s.(3p.)
- Barry, John Stetson, 1819-1872. Letters to J.J.French:
  - A.L.s.; Scituate, 30 Apr 1855., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Scituate, 7 May 1855., 1s.(1p.)
- Barry, Sir John Wolfe Wolfe, 1836-1918. A.L.s.to Sir Matthew Nathan; [London ] 14 Jan 1911., 1s.(1p.)
  *60M-136. Gift of Mr. and Mrs. J. F. Fleming, Dec 1960.
- Barry, Joseph, 1828?- A.L.s. to William H.Kinsley; Harpers Ferry, 24 Feb 1883., 1s.(4p.)
- Barstow, Wilson A.L.s. to W.Stuart; 5 Jan 1867,New York, 1s.(4p.)
- Bartha, Stephen C T.L.s. to Thomas Wolfe; Astoria, 8 Apr 1930., 1s.(1p.) torn.
  *82M-39. Gift of Mrs. George Kates, Feb 1983.
- Barthélemy, Jean Jacques, 1716-1795. A.L.s. to Fagart Merlin; Paris, 15 Sep [1785], 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (24). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Barthelemy Saint-Hilaire, Jules A.L.s. to [ ] Lee-Childe; Versailles, 27 Apr 1872., 1s.(2p.)
- Bartholomew, Charles Lewis, 1869- A.L.s. to Erastus Brainerd; Seattle, [n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bartholomew, Valentine, 1799-1879. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p.] 23 Sep 1857., 1s.(1p.)
- Bartlett, Israel MS.L. (copy) to Moses Grant; Haverhills, 16 Sep 1803., 1s. (3p.)
  With MS. copy of a report from the first parish church of Haverhills concerning the dismissal of the Rev. Abiel Abbot, 1s. (1p.)
- Bartlett, John, 1820-1905. Letters to [Francis Henry] Underwood:
  - A.L.s.; Cambridge, 12 Sep 1892., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; Cambridge, 5 Dec 1892., 1s.(1p.)
- Bartlett, John Russell, 1805-1886. A.L.s. to Mrs.[ ] Allen; New York, 29 Mar 1847., 1s.(2p.)
- Bartlett, John Russell, 1805-1886. A.L.s. to George F. Geer; Providence, 23 Nov 1869., 1s.(1p.)
- Bartlett, Samuel Colcord, 1817-1898. A.L.s. to [ ] Hanover, N.H., 21 Oct 1879., 1s.(1p.)
- Bartlett, Sidney, 1799-1899. A.L.s. to [Lemuel?] Shaw; [n.p.] 9 Jul [ ]., 1s.(3p.)
- Bartol, Cyrus Augustus, 1813-1900. A.L.s. to William Buell Sprague; Boston, 16 Feb 1859., 1s.(1p.)
  Simes collection, n.d.
- Bartol, Cyrus Augustus, 1813-1900. A.L.s. to [ ]; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bartol, Cyrus Augustus, 1813-1900. A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Barton, Bernard, 1784-1849. A.L.s. to [ ]; Woodbridge, 11 Apr 1846., 1s.(3p.)
  With an engraving of Barton in his study as letterhead, and including a 20-line poem entitled Stanzas.
  r.f. X5.2F
  Gift of Mrs. James T. Fields, 4 Dec 1915.
- Barton, Bernard, 1784-1849. A.L.s.(initials) to [ ]; [n.p.,n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
  Fragment only of a longer letter.
- Barton, [Mrs ] A.L. (3d person) to [David] Garrick; [London] 10 Feb 1767., 1s. (3p.)
  Mostly in verse.
  *54M-249. Purchased from the estate of David M. Little, 1954.
- Barton, William Paul Crillon, 1786-1856. A.L.s. to Dr. Washington; [n.p.] 14 Jan 1836., 1s.(2p.)
- Barzaghi, Francesco A.L.s. to Honorable Société; Milan, 27 Jul 1886., 1s.(1p.)
- Bascom, Ezekiel Lysander A.L.s. to John Locke; Augusta, Ga., 23 Feb 1833., 1s.(4p.)
- Basing, George Sclater-Booth, 1st baron, 1826-1894. A.L.s.to [ ]; [London] 2 Aug 1872., 2s.(4p.)
- Basire, James, 1769-1835, engraver. View of part of Urless Farm in Corscombe, Dorsetshire: engraving,1815., 1s.
  After a 1747 painting by P. A. Rysbrach.; Urles Farm in Corscombe, Dorset (England), belonged to Thomas Hollis, 1720-1774.
  *2003M-64 Gift of George Truett Hollis, 2004 Apr. 21.
- Baskervill, William Malone, 1850- A.L.s.to [Edwin] Ginn; Nashville, 20 Dec 1887., 2s.(2p.)
  Kittredge estate, n.d.
- Baskett, John, d. 1742. Printed D.s.; [London] 16 Jul 1706., 1s.(2p.)
  *61M-11(1). Purchased with the Wells fund, 17 Aug 1961.
- Baskett, John, d. 1742. MS.D.s.; [London] 24 Feb 1738., 1s.(4p.)
  Treasury order for payment to Baskett as King's Printer. Also signed by Robert Walpole,; Giles Earle, and Thomas Winnington, and others.
  *61M-11(2). Purchased with the Wells fund, 17 Aug 1961.
- Bassett, George A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 8 Apr 1828., 1s.(1p.)
- Bassett, Henry, b. 1803. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 8 Apr [1828], 1s.(1p.)
- Bassett, J.S.1920.
- Batacchi, Domenico, 1748-1802. A.L.s. to Luigi Migliavesi; [n.p.] 15 Feb 1798., 1s.(2p.)
  *71M-79. Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, 10 May 1972.
- Bateman, James, 1814-1849. A.L.s. to [ ]; Highbury Vale, 26 Jul 1841., 1s.(1p.)
  Also a clipping.
- Bates, Albert Carlos, 1865- A.L.s. to Ernest Lewis Gay; Hartford, 5 Apr 1911., 5s.(5p.) env.
- Bates, Arlo, 1850-1918. A.L.s. to Mrs. [ ] Wendell; [n.p.] Oct 1, 1887., 1s.(4p.)
- Bates, Arlo, 1850-1918. When the dead return [first line of poem A.MS.s.; [n.p., n.d.], 1s.(1p.)
- Bates, John Lewis, 1859-. Typed L.s. to Col. William D. Sohier; Boston, 5 Nov 1903., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(31). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bates, John Lewis, 1859-. Typed L.s. to Col. William D. Sohier; Boston, 16 Nov 1904., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(32). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bates, Joshua, 1776-1854. Letters to Solomon Lincoln:
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 21 Dec 1840., 1s.(3p.)
  - A.L.s.; Dudley, 9 Nov 1853., 1s.(3p.)
    Simes Collection, n.d.
- Bates, Joshua, 1776-1854. A.L.s. to William Buell Sprague; Middlebury, Vt., 21 Aug 1830., 1s.(2p.)
- Bates, Joshua, 1776-1854. A.L.s. to William B. Swett; Charlestown, 24 Jun 1807., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181(30). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Bates, Joshua, 1788-1864. A.L.s. to Elliot Woodberry; London, 25 Jul 1823., 1s.(2p.)
- Bates, Katerine Lee, 1859-1929. Letters to Florence Milner:
  - T.L.s.; Wellesley, 17 Dec 1923., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Wellesley, 15 Apr 1924., 1s.(1p.)
- Bates, Walter, 1760-1842. Copyright assignment to Thomas Green Woodward: document signed; New Haven (Conn.),1816 Nov. 18., 1 folder
  Copyright for Bates's A mysterious stranger, or Memoirs of Henry More Smith. With a signed receipt for 1,000 copies of the book, 1817 Jan. 1, on verso.
  *95M-47. Gift of Roger E. Stoddard, 1996 Feb. 6.
- Bathurst, Henry, bp. of Norwich, d. 1837. A.L.s. to [ ]; Norwich, Eng. 2 Sep 1823., 1s.(1p.)
- Bathurst, Henry, bp. of Norwich, 1744-1837. A. signature on cover to [John] Yelloly; London, 20 Dec 1833., 1s.(1p.)
  Presented by E. J. Wendell, 1918.
- Baudelaire, Charles, 1821-1867. A.D.s.; Paris, 27 Dec 1861., 1s.(1p.)
  Note for 100 fr. received from the Société des gens de lettres.
  Removed from *57-1000.
  Purchased with the Amy Lowell fund, 7 Apr 1958.
- Baudelaire, Charles, 1821-1867. A.L.s. to [ ] Berardi; Paris, 19 Aug 1863., 1s.(3p.)
  Offering for publication his translations of "The mystery of Marie Roget" and another piece by Poe.
  Gift of Lucien Wulsin, Dec 1963.
- Baudelaire, Charles, 1821-1867. A.L.s.(initials) to [Auguste] Poulet-Malassis; [Paris, 19 Oct 1859], 1s.(2p.)
  *55M-139. Purchased with the Amy Lowell Fund. Presented by Scribner Book Store, 1 Feb 1956.
- Bausset, Louis François de, cardinal, 1748-1824. A.L.s. to [ ] Hardy; [n.p.] Sep 1816., 1s.(3p.)
  *49M-187 (25). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Baxter, Charles, 1809-1879. A.L.s. to [ ] Duncan; [London] [n.d.], 1s.(2p.)
- Baxter, Charles, 1809-1879. Letters to [ ] Howard:
  - A.L.s.; [London][1834]., 1s.(1p.)
  - A.L.s.; [London] 5 Apr 1836., 1s.(1p.)
- Baxter, Charles, 1809-1879. A.L.s. to John Watkins; [London] 19 Feb 1867., 1s.(1p.)
- Baxter, George, 1804-1867. A.L.s. to [ ]; [London] 25 Sep 1841., 1s.(1p.)
- Baxter, George, 1804-1867. A.L.s. to [ ] Limpol?; [London, 7 Aug 1842.], 1s.(2p.)
- Baxter, Richard, 1615-1691. A.L.s. to Richard Sargeant; [n.p.] 14 May [16--], 1s.(4p.)
  *53M-135F. Purchased from Goodspeed's Book Store, 27 Apr 1954.
- Baxter, Richard, 1615-1691. A.L.s.(photostat) to [ ]; [n.p.] 14 Jan 1653/1654., 1s.(1p.)
  The original is owned by Alexander William Armour, Princeton, N.J.
- Bayard, James Asheton, 1799-1880. A.L.s. to William Young; Wilmington, 14 Apr 1835., 1s. (2p.)
  *43M-893. Gift of Mrs. Bailey Aldrich, 1943.
- Bayard, Richard Henry, 1796-1868. A.L.s. to C.A. Davison; Washington, 6 Feb 1842., 1s.(1p.)
- Bayard, Robert. Printed D.s.; New York, 21 Feb 1826., 1s.(1p.)
  Medical certificate of William Walsh.
  Purchased with the Fine fund, n.d.
- Bayard, Samuel, 1765-1840. A.L.s. to [ ]; Princeton, 16 Apr 1827., 1s.(2p.)
- Bayard, Thomas Francis, 1828-1898. Letters to Adam Badeau,1831-1895.
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 14 Jan 1884., 1s.(2p.)
  - A.L.s.; Washington, 6 Dec 1887., 1s.(3p.)
- Bayard, Thomas Francis, 1828-1898. Printed D.s.; Washington, 16 Jun 1888., 1s.(1p.)
  Passport for Cornelia Warren.
- Bayle, Pierre, 1647-1706. A.L.s.to [ ]; Rotterdam, 27 Oct 1704., 1s.(4p.)
  *57M-95. Deposited by George Benson Weston, 27 Dec 1957. Later bequest.
- Bayle, Pierre, 1647-1706. A.L.s.to [Mme ] de Bayle; Geneva, 21 Sep 1671., 1s.(3p.)
  *58M-54. Presented by William H. Schab, Oct 1958.
- Bayley, Sir John, 1763-1841. A.L.s. to Sir Charles Wetherell; Ramsgate, 10 Oct 1831., 1s.(1p.) env.
- Baylies, Francis, 1783-1852. A.L.s. to Theophilus Parsons; Washington, 14 Feb 1823., 1s.(2p.)
- Baylor, Frances Courtenay, 1848-1920. A.L.s. to Lippincott, firm, publishers: Philadelphia, 7 Sep 1892., 1s.(2p.)
- Bayly, Thomas Henry, 1810-1856. A.L.s. to C. A. Davison; Washington, 17 Jun 1844., 1s.(1p.)
- Bayne, Howard Randolph, 1851- A.L.s. to William Winter; Staten Island 2 Oct 1903., 1s.(1p.)
- Bazin, René, 1853-1932. A.L.s. to [ ]; Paris, 20 Feb 1909., 1s.(2p.)
  *49M-187 (26). From the Collection of French Academicians formed by M. Victor Deseglise, ca. 1920.
- Bazire, Claude, 1764-1794. A.D.s.; Paris, 9 Oct 1792., 1s.(1p.)
  *45M-181 (33). Gift of James Freeman Clarke, Feb 1946.
- Beach, Amy Marcy (Cheney) 1867- A.L.s. to Miss [ ] Jewett: [n.p.] 9 Feb [ ]., 1s.(2p.)
  Removed from x5.1F.
- Beach, Edward Latimer, 1918- A.L.s. to Frederick Wagner; Mystic, Conn., 15 Jul 1961., 1s.(2p.) env.
  *79M-37(64). Gift of Frederick Wagner, 25 June 1979.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881. A.L.s. (initial) to J. C. Adderly; [London] 22 Jul 1862., 1s. (3p.)
  *46M-151. Presented by Dr. William Inglis Morse; 4 Jan 1947.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881. A.L.s. to Henry Colburn; [Bradenham, Buckinghamshire] 14 Feb 1830., 1s.(2p.)
  *52M-255. Presented by Mr. Curt H. Reisinger. Purchased from Maggs Brothers, 4 June 1953.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881. A.L.s. to Henry Colburn; Bradenham [Buckinghamshire, 10 Feb 1836], 1s.(3p.)
  *52M-256. Presented by Mr. Curt H. Reisinger. Purchased from Maggs Brothers, 4 June 1953.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881 A.L.s. to the Committee of the Fremantle testimonial; Shrewsbury, 13 Jan 1842., 1s.(3p.) env.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881. A.L.s.to [ ]; [London, n.d.], 1s.(4p.)
  *57JM-34(1). Bequest of Lee M. Friedman, 1957.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881. A.L.s. (B D) to [ ]; [London,1832?], 1s.(2p.)
  *42M-499(6). Gift of Dr. Harris Kennedy, 26 Jan 1943.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of, 1804-1881. MS.D.s.; [London?] 18 Jul 1861., 4f.(8p.) f∘.
  Agreement between Disraeli and Routledge,; Warne Routledge concerning books by Disraeli and his father.
  *50M-129. Purchased with the Bemis fund from Maggs Brothers Ltd., Sept 1950.
- Beaconsfield, Benjamin Disraeli, 1st earl of,1804-1881. [Pass to gallery, House of Commons] MS.s.; 15 May 1867.